okay
welcome thanks it's uh March 15 2023
we're in meeting 20 of
cohort two
in our first discussion on chapter nine
so
as we begin this discussion of nine
is there any
General comment or question about nine
that anyone wants to bring up
one one part on nine is it at least
points the direction towards
an Avenue that many people who are
interested in learning and applying
active inference want to go down which
is
to make generative models
yes that help us understand different
cognitive systems
and also have models that can accept
empirical data
so that we can enact the tale of two
densities
so we can use the model in the
generative Direction
to go from
specified parameters to
output data sets of synthetic data kind
of like generative AI but then also to
recognize
outcomes in the world or data
and then update or parameterize our
generative models
from those data
ends it's that Tale of Two densities
the generative density and the
recognition density the ability to run
these models both ways
to generate valid synthetic data from a
generative model
and if you design your experiment so
that those data which are generated
are also actually being generated in the
real world then you can just instantly
plug it back in
um
and we'll I'm sure unpack and explore
more so we'll go through the chapter but
is there any just general comment or
general thoughts on chapter nine first
foreign
so let's look at one previous question
so how did chapter four on the
generative model relate to chapter nine
as we're getting close to the end of the
book chapter six was a recipe it was
about applying active inference
chapter four we were learning the
necessary prerequisites in chapter one
and two and three were the roads to
chapter four
then chapter five we got the
neurobiology and some examples chapter
six we got the recipe
chapter 7 and 8 was the discrete time
and continuous time
generative models
and now we're in chapter nine
where we're learning how to solve
problems and it's about getting one's
hands dirty with case studies and
problem solving
we'll see this in the figure
upcoming
a key distinction is between the
subjective model
and the objective model
there's different readings of the first
sentence and in some readings it could
be seen as playing fast and loose with
instrumentalism and realism
so the subjective model though is that
which the subject
is that that which is subject specific
from the subject's perspective now it
turns out that it is a map that we're
making from the subjects perspective
so it isn't the actual territory
of the subjectivity
but it is
from the subjects perspective
and then to meet that and make the full
model
we are going to have an objective model
which doesn't mean that it's the one and
only it means that it's our view from
the outside
seeing that thing as an object
this entire setup
with a tale of two densities and the the
metabasian
enables
us to make Bayesian cognitive models and
think about experimentation in a
Bayesian context
which lets us talk about Bayes optimal
cognition
in different systems
and one area that that has been
especially relevant is in computational
phenotyping
this chapter deals with a utility
of active inference formulations in
analyzing data from behavioral
experiments
it's going beyond the proof of principle
simulation so in the proof of principle
domain we have the Jumping Frog in the
hands we have the rat in the tmas and so
on
and here active inference is going to be
used to answer scientific questions
since the subjective GM
is the generator of behavior in active
inference
then
the scientific hypotheses that we're
going to entertain
about the causes and consequences of
phenotype
must be in terms of hypotheses about
alternative generative models
so
the challenge is to
just like an abductive logic challenge
generate a portfolio or spaces
of alternative generative models
cognitive models
and then
ask for a given string of observations
what the evidence is for difference
alternative hypotheses provided
and then at that point one could take a
more classical or frequentist approach
they could also take a more pure
Bayesian approach and ask about like the
Bayes factor and the relative support of
different models
but the Upstream
part is to generate alternative
generative models
explicitly or implicitly by specifying
State spaces or possibilities
and then chapter 9 is when we're
plugging in empirical data and then
going to ask about which of those
generative models or spaces within the
possibilities of the GMS
have what evidence with respect to the
observables
if you have any thought or questions
just totally go for it otherwise we'll
just continue to like walk through it on
the first discussion
Michael go for it
yeah I'm uh I mean I guess you'll still
come to it but I'm struggling with this
mathematics uh very much and last time
we had this interesting discussion about
temporal
models the difference between chapter 7
and chapter and chapter eight and I was
thinking that for my data that I have
with this gay State and the keystrokes
and all this these temporal models would
be
perhaps much better Suited
but then we discussed about these
different uh
kinds of derivations and I'm really
Unsure how what that implies whether I
should
um
find a way to express my data in kinds
of waves so that one can compute somehow
derivations from this or
um so we did discussed about The
Disappearance of of time in these models
and I I'm really struggling to
understand what that means in my data
that I have but I don't know whether
this really relates to what you were
saying before
yeah it was it's definitely it's it's um
it's a it's a experience and a challenge
when you have an actual uh data set and
for people who are already
experimentalists
it's not like we can just dream up the
most creative generative model and then
build a lab to record those data in many
cases were actually constrained in what
we can do or we already have the data
set
and then we're going to work backwards
from the data set to generative models
yep that's the case in my case yes yeah
yeah so I mean one
um
um uh Beware all who pass this point is
everything just like everything that led
to the collection of your data was an
experimentalist's choice you could have
collected more or different
um participants you could have done this
or that in the data collection
and now let's just say that we're in the
analysis phase
everything Downstream everything about
the structure of the generative model
and so on is all going to be modeler's
degrees of freedom
so
we are looking for different spaces to
specify
and then different portfolios of
generative models to test against and
one of the great things about Bayesian
statistics
is that wildly disparate
models architecturally
can be compared through the base factor
and the Bayesian information Criterion
so just a explain why that's relevant
relative to the um frequency statistics
When comparing frequentist statistical
models
one of the only principled ways to
actually test for which model is better
is the hierarchical likelihood ratio
test
so you can say I have two strictly
nested models I have factor a and Factor
B and now I'm going to test for an
interaction effect of a x b
and then you can ask whether there's a
statistically significant Improvement by
taking on that interaction effect but if
you said I have a model with a XB and
then I have a model with B and C and C
and D and DNA and X and Y those models
cannot be directly compared because
they're
um
likelihoods
are not comparable
in contrast
Bayesian models can be compared in
various ways
the base Factor the Bic accuracy minus
complexity
free energy
even when there's a very very different
model anatomies
so it's not even like you have to decide
whether you want to do only a discrete
or only a continuous time generative
model
and hopefully as the software pipelines
become more developed
it'll be like you'll specify all the
different channels that your data can
flow through
and then see how diff wildly different
models
match up with the data
and look at their relative evidence or
the areas that they fit well or don't in
and you still might have to prune that
down
in some talk or paper
but also maybe it'll be possible to
share those computational resources also
with that kind of high bandwidth
um but yeah we'll we'll return to it so
two reasons why we wanna
fit data like why chapter nine
the first is to estimate parameters of
interest from a group
those kinds of computational phenotypes
might be useful for some other setting
the second reason is to compare
alternative hypotheses
so here we have in the simplest case two
groups
and we want to ask if there is a
difference
in some parameter in the cognitive model
a related
reason to use computational phenotyping
is potentially even for one person or
one group or it could be for two groups
is to compare two different models
against one another and ask which one
has different
um evidence
and so these are the two agendas
estimating parameters given a cognitive
model
and
evaluation among models given data
that's the same hypothesis
you have the same hypothesis you just
replace the model
same data so like uh like uh let's just
say in the first case what this would
look like would be people who have
condition X or not
I'm going to measure their attention
with with this given attention model I'm
going to test if there's a significant
difference in this attention parameter
this one would say I have two attention
models I have one where attention is a
single layer model and I have one where
there's like a you know a nested model
on attention
and now on the whole data set or on just
this one person I'm going to ask which
of these two cognitive models is more
consistent with the data that I see
and and this
um these two agendas
are perfectly compatible
with different terms Within
Bayes theorem
which
is a tight
synthesis
of the
kind of Foley Bayesian epistemology
it's like we're doing Bayesian science
with Bayesian statistics
we're approaching
our data collection and Analysis
in an optimal information setting
okay now we get to figure nine one with
the objective and the subjective so does
anyone want to give a thought on figure
9.1 what they see here or what they see
this figure doing in the context of the
book
okay just to give a first thought then
again just raise your hander or write in
the chat or anything
that we saw in
chapters four
five
seven eight all those generative models
all those base graphs
those are in the center in the dashed
line
and so it's a map
but it's a map that we're constructing
as if it were a view from the inside
so here's the mouse in the T Maze and
here's the pomdp in this case it's it's
a discrete time you can tell because it
has the past present and future
transition Matrix and so on
and so we've made a discrete time model
of the mouse
in the teammates so it's the as if
Mouse's View From the Inside
and and that's what makes sense when
we're doing computational phenotyping we
don't want to do model selection on
um omniscient mice
because we don't think that that
exists in the world so the kinds of
constraints that we think actually are
uh justifiable in the world like the
only input is sensory and the only
outputs are actions
those constraints are embodied within
the GM that we make for the subject
but the subject is also the object of
our study
the object of our study or the system of
interest of our study is that
Mouse in the teammates
and so with respect to how we designed
that teamaze experiment
and whether we do it with one trial on
one day or we do it with this other
block design or we have it replicated
across Laboratories
those experimental parameters
that are action selections from us
can be understood as being drawn
from distributions of possible
experiments
and
what are action selections by the
experimenter
are being passed into the subjects model
as an observation
what is passed out of the subject
through action
is the input
for the Observer
so we're kind of wrapping
the generative models that we saw
in chapter four Etc
calling those subjective models
not to mean that they're willy-nilly but
just to say that they are as if from the
subject's perspective
and then wrapping that
as a behavioral researcher in an
objective model not to mean that it's
the one only true model but it's the one
from the outside with the subject as
object
and this is called meta Bayesian
so in some ways this is a
formalization
of
ethology
with the cognitive modeling twist
because we're explicitly saying that
we're interested in this cognitive or
internal map Michael
has has this to do with um
self-evidencing experimental that they
put in the data and they get the results
and then they mother
the subject in between in such a way
that the expectations become true that
the input output relations and so is it
has it to do with itself evidencing
ideas
yeah the experimental
yeah it's very interesting
um like our subjective model
we can see why that is set up in a way
to be self-evidising
we can say that the mouse is moving
around in the team A's
so that it reduces Divergence so that it
can be the kind of mouse that it expects
and prefers to be we can understand its
diverse behavioral Selections in light
of self-evidizing
if we're going to consider ourselves in
a Bayesian light as well
then also
that entails a certain kind of
epistemological self-evidencing
now in the extreme or in one simple
reading self-evidencing would be like
you write down the number four oh I
wonder what number four great write down
the number four look at the number it's
four
well that isn't what self-evidising
means
anymore than for the organism it means
to stay in the dark room
which has been a point of philosophical
contention for like literally 10 years
people say well if organisms are acting
to reduce surprise or to self-evidence
why don't they just stay in the dark
room
dark room challenge
you know Throw Down The Gauntlet and
it's like
right if the generative model didn't
have survival requirements and its only
imperative was to have the reduced
Divergence with a photon distribution
you would and you do see that behavior
but that's not what organisms do
and Maps aren't territories so if you
actually built a realistic generative
model
you would find it self-evidencing
doesn't just mean staying in the dark
room it also means self-evidencing for
temperature and thirst and all these
other drives
so self-evidencing by the researcher
plays out
in a way that would need its own
generative model to be specific about
but for example if the researcher says
my commitment is to maximum information
experimentation
I'm not trying to Simply confirm what my
friend told me
my commitments and expectations
preference is for maximally informative
experiment design
then the experiment that they design
can be understood as self-evidising
even if the data points are maximally
surprising
that would be the point
Ali
and also about
self-evidencing
is in recent literature
um
especially since 2019
there's two distinct way of formulating
uh self-evident self-evidencing one is
in terms of Bayesian model evidence
which is the approach taken uh in this
chapter as well and one is in the the
terms of lagrangian of the autonomous
Paths of active particles so these
autonomous paths are actually or uh in
other words these lagrangians are
actually the expected green energy which
can by themselves decomposed into two
separate terms corresponding with
expected costs on one hand and expected
Information Gain
so uh in this kind of formulation the
expected cost is the surprisal of
sensory paths which is also what's
referred to as uh the sensory
surprisal or the self self evidencing of
the self-organization systems so uh
there are slight uh or there's some
subtle differences between these two
formulations but ultimately they
converge onto same results providing
I mean a description of the behavior of
these systems in uh or in particular
active particles uh in the environment
in terms of minimizing their expected
free energy
thank you
um
when we set up
the ethological moment in this way
it's an active inference problem
so it can be approached using all of the
amazing tools
that are being developed
our focus is on active and specifically
discrete time
however the generic methods may be used
with other likelihood functions
so other normative models of behavior
in active inference our normativity is
around self-evidencing
things should persistent things should
minimize or bound their surprise but
there's no issue with having a
subjective model with a different
normativity
that it should maximize reward as per a
utility function defined
now there will be
a generic inference scheme that can be
used for metabasian inference
then there's going to be a recipe and
then a key example
readers uninterested in certain details
are invited to skip 9.39.4 okay we'll
keep that in mind
parametric empirical base
is a technique that's used to jump start
a Bayesian analysis
with empirical data
so a common question by adherence and
critics in Bayesian statistics is like
well what priors should I choose
because there's no such thing as a
unbiased or a non-biased prior
there's the uniform distribution like
the flat probability distribution but
even that
is over a certain interval
and it still embodies
a prior
albeit one that is uniform across the
range
but there's other situations where the
uniform distribution is not even a
possible selection
for example you can't have a uniform
distribution across all possible Heights
of trees at some point you just got to
be like you know objects have this range
of sizes
and so there's always this question
about selection of priors and Hyper
priors and and so on
now in many cases in practice
it can be shown that it doesn't matter
that much for example somebody will show
that with two wildly Divergent prior
distributions there's so much signal in
the data that it converges to the same
posterior so that's often used as
evidence like hey we tried different
priors and we always got the same
conversions
even with different families of priors
so we feel like this signal is being
driven by patterns in the data and it's
not an aberration because of our choice
of like a very opinionated prior
so that's one strategy people take
presentation of alternative priors
another
approach that can be taken
and it's not exclusive to what was
previously mentioned is parametric
empirical base and so in this situation
empirical data are used to kick start
setting the priors
so we're going to be measuring the
height of children in the whole school
first we're going to measure one
classroom and then we're going to use
the mean and the variance of that
classroom
as our prior moving forward for the
other classrooms
so it's just a way to take empirical
data
and use the empirical data summary
statistics
like mean invariance for gaussian
to jump start subsequent Bayesian
analyzes including of the data that
generated that prior now that analysis
by itself won't be super informative
because you kind of already described
the maximum likelihood solution for that
one data set
but with sub sampling and so on there's
some ways to make PEB really useful
all right so 9.3 9.4 it was like
reminded that they're not essential so
we'll move a little faster through them
but we can return to it
um
next time
okay
here we have the variables that are
being used in the metabasian image in 9
figure 9.1
and there's a focus on the likelihood
function
and um
Bayesian model evidence
is
closely linked to surprise or
self-evidising because the model with
the most evidence
is the one that is least surprised by
data
so sometimes we're talking more about
maximizing likelihood other times
minimizing the surprise
but the tuning of the parameters
is not going to
clash between those approaches
pi
are those policy selections
and so pi
is going to be based upon a minimization
of free energy over all the pies
so this is like active
free energy minimization of the
generative model not of the territory of
the GM
is going to be used as the imperative
for Action selection which is what we
observed from The Mouse and the
teammates
so if we have the model that does best
at predicting their behavior
then we've done a good compromised job
on the subjective
perception cognition action
and there's just a mention of this
temperature parameter shaky handedness
which is just kind of fun to like think
about even just from an intuition
perspective
where in the shaky hand limit the high
temperature everything is shaking a lot
it eradicates
differences in the likelihood of taking
different actions
like if something is just vibrating it
just ends up making all action selection
choices equally likely
whereas like in the sort of
um short-handed limit
then
you follow either your habits or your
free energy minimization
without further hindrance
so
sure handed
optimization of policy
shaky handed
if and if it's soft Max is one
then you're sampling from the posterior
so there's two actions and your
posterior evaluation is 60 40. if this
parameter is one you you select those
policies sixty and forty percent of the
time respectively
if you turn up the temperature it
converges back to 50 50 and if you turn
down the temperature you're always going
to select the higher
um likelihood one
there are some details on the LaPlace
um assumption
there's probably a lot of detail that
could be gone into but
LaPlace puts a quadratic function
that is censored at the maximum
likelihood solution to a distribution so
if it's bimodal there's two humps to the
distribution LaPlace will get stuck at
one of them
or you'll get other kinds of issues like
it'll be stuck at one but very over
dispersed and so on so this isn't
approximating the distribution
completely but it turns out it's a super
computable way
that in many reasonable situations does
really well
now we return to the PEB
so
we want to ask regular Anova type
statistical modeling questions
here
we have a linear model
this is kind of like SPM Style
where X is a design Matrix
it's also used in linear
regressor models won't go into this in
too much more detail but this is kind of
like saying
just like you could do a linear
regression with a design Matrix on
height
you can do a linear regression with a
design Matrix on generative model
parameters
and still test for an effect of age by
height on attention or something like
that
9.5
instructions for model based analysis
Ollie go for it
yeah I just wanted to point out
um the relation between the uh LaPlace
assumption and the form of the
recognition density because
um very briefly uh assuming I mean
LaPlace assumption uh mathematically
leads to this assumption that that the
shape of the recognition density would
be necessarily a gaussian density so in
that case the variation of free energy
would be equivalent to Gibbs energy but
without that LaPlace assumption then we
would have a variational free energy
equals Gibbs energy minus the entropy of
the recognition density and by
recognition density I mean the
probability that the approximate
probability density for hidden inputs
um hidden input variables under a
certain generative model
thank you
many times
getting to a gaussian or a quadratic
is
simplifying
it's symmetric
it has the minimum number of parameters
too to describe like the mean and the
scaling
the mean the variance
but that doesn't mean distributions in
the world are like that
however for ones that are even roughly
shaped
like that like they have a central
tendency
these kinds of symmetric models can be
like super super effective because they
have very very well established methods
for solving
okay
now we're going to get to instructions
for the model based analysis so
definitely contrast slash juxtapose this
with the recipe from chapter six so in
six we were kind of coming to the system
what are we modeling why are we doing it
what structurally
are we looking to include in our GM
how are we going to specifically set up
that GM
and then how are we going to set up the
generative process okay doesn't have to
be in order but these are what we'll
need to figure out now in chapter 9
we have some instructions for how to go
from not just building a GM like we saw
in six but to
using the GM for GM based analysis
so
collecting behavioral data including
metadata or demographic data
two
formulate a pomdp
I I think here they could have said
construct a GM as per chapter 6.
but they're focusing like they mentioned
above on the discrete time case
so that's why they're focusing on the
pomdp
specify a likelihood function
that is going to simulate behavior and
quantify the likelihood of observed
actions
so
we started with data
then we formed a pomdp basically like it
was laid out in chapter six
it turns out we're doing a pmdp like
chapter seven but it's basically like
formulating the GM
and now we're going to actually be using
that GM
for doing the kinds of papers that
people write about where this age group
had with this statistical confidence
level a higher likelihood of this or
that
um
how should the model be used to
calculate a likelihood
specification of priors
that's where
um
you can take a zero centered
approach or again one could use
parametric empirical base
to just say oh previous studies found
this distribution so that's going to be
my prior distribution
um
here's our prior probability
and our likelihood
what we need now is the posterior
probability in the model evidence
likelihood function
prior
solving for now with data
posterior distributions and evidence
so
we put information in on the front half
of Bayes equation now we're solving for
the second half of Base equation and
there are routines in SPM in Matlab that
help with this
lastly perform the group level analysis
this is also an opportunity for using
PEB
or you can do any other kind of truly
wide variety of statistical methods
you could
fall back to frequentism and just do a
t-test
just say all right I had 17 in this
group and 35 in this group and we got a
t-test to see if this attention
parameter was significantly different
you could use a canonical variate
analysis
or an independent contrast analysis or
principal component analysis
any statistical method that you would
see in any paper
this is just doing statistics at this
point
a little bit more detail
and figure 9.2
is showing the six step inversion
procedure
collect the data
make the model
specify the likelihood function
P of utilda remember back to 91 util
does the observed Behavior
so we're doing behavioral modeling
what we're interested in is the
distribution
of probabilities of of behaviors given
Theta o and m
so now we've kind of like
specified the pumdp for the mouse in the
in the maze
but we've pulled back our likelihood
function
to in a way abstract or insulate from
all of those subjective model parameters
such that our statistical analysis is
only about
objective model parameters
so I'd be like if we were making a
cognitive model of a decision to take X
or Y Behavior
we'd want to do that then collect the
data on the behavior
and then do a demographic analysis on
how X or Y is related with this or that
and those statistics are not an appeal
to the cognitive model of the decision
maker
they're actually a layer of descriptive
statistics
that will be absolutely familiar to
anyone who's done behavioral modeling in
the lab it's just a slightly different
way of looking at them
but it can be seen as doing model
evaluation and estimation
using statistics
in a way that doesn't mention any of the
inner cognitive model parameters
because things have been framed in this
nice tan metabasian way
we can do the tale of two densities
and here is kind of a visualization of
what the um
t-test would look like those those error
bars could be bootstrapped et cetera et
cetera but let's just imagine that
they're from a t-test so here's five
groups
and here we have some parameter that we
modeled
their novelty seeking something or some
other specific model inside
and then we can ask like
is there more variance within or among
These Bars
and maybe you see you know a bar with an
asterisk here these two are
indistinguishable but they're both
significantly different than these three
and you know this one is significantly
different from that one but not that so
you see those kinds of like regular
Anova type statistics
here in a Bayesian setup
so specification of the GM chapter 6 and
all that
allows us to do statistics on it
just if you had some Advanced model of
materials properties
and then we were just testing which one
was like harder or softer
um
before analyzing actual data we may want
to check face validity
by generating fictive data
so taking just a look at it visually
and also doing parameter recovery
so that means can you identify or
recover
parameters or do you have issues with
your model like collinearity
where there's two parameters that are
like they're so covariate with each
other
that sometimes you'll run the model and
it will explain the data equally well
with wildly different combinations of
those two parameters just for example
um and again classical SPM like angle
with a design Matrix
it's kind of amazing how it works but
the design Matrix encodes all of the
experimental
metadata
and then you have like a matrix of
regressors
and you just smash the design Matrix
into this beta
and somehow the dimensions work out and
it's like what you'd want to know
like in SPM it'll be one Matrix with
this is the um the age and so on of the
of the patients
and here's a big Matrix with all of the
fmri data
and you just smash them together and it
and then it sets up this
if it's all set up properly
okay and then just we'll look at these
upcoming sections but then talk more
with open questions and and look at any
other details
there's going to be an analysis of the
Mirza at all socket eye movement
and
smooth pursuit of eye movement atoms
and mersa
smooth tracking of eye movement
on the left atoms
discrete tracking of eye movements mersa
not much more said than that
obviously there's papers to go back to
and those are even generative models
that we can use
replicate them and modify them
models of false inference
so this is going to be approaching that
kind of challenging Nexus of well if
it's Bayes optimal then how is their
maladaptive Behavior
how can people have delusions
How can there be the accommodation of
chemical changes
that that just fundamentally alter
the substrate of cognition
table 9.1 has a sample of examples
that um
our papers
exploring computational pathology in
primarily humans
but almost surely vertebrates
addiction impulsivity compulsivity
delusions hallucination
interpersonal and personality disorder
ocular motor syndrome
pharmacotherapy
prefrontal syndromes visual neglect
disorders of interceptive inference
so just
giving us some examples
and the notes
tend to be defining what that pathology
was
um
operationalized as
by those studies
and then briefly
what kind of generative models were used
to support what new explanations
predictions or control opportunities are
presented when we have for example an
active model of oculomotor syndrome as
opposed to some other framework for
describing that behavior
um
a useful way of thinking about causes of
pathological behaviors to think about
the prior belief used for policies
and how each part of this may be
disrupted to give rise to abnormal
policy selection
so one could look at a figure and just
imagine that we're dealing with a very
simple
uh mouse-like patient
on the top here
um
or um
just looking at it here
if we're interested in that behavioral
policy selection component
that is uh conditioned on
preferences and affordances or habits
so that's why they mentioned c and e
because maybe there's a group of people
who are repeatedly or compulsively
taking a given Behavior
but again just totally simplifying
making this up
there might be some who prefer that
behavior and understand the consequences
of their action so they engage in the
selection of the behavior because they
expect slash prefer it
in another case it actually might not be
aligned with the preferences but it has
become habitual
in which case there's a difference
cognitive model parameterization
and potentially different consequences
or treatment opportunities
however
the experiment needs to be carefully
designed
to resolve those possibilities
which is why a great
advance
is to be able to basically not just
pre-register what you're going to do
but to do the statistical power analysis
and ask which regions of experimental
State space are going to be Bayesian
optimal for for example distinguishing
two groups of people
some of whom have a habitual bias and
others have a strong prior preference
for something
but it's not just like any given set of
experimental data are going to resolve
this
because these are not measurable things
in the world
they're inferred parameters in our
cognitive map
so it's not just going to happen because
we tried
that being said we can make the GM ahead
of time and do the simulations do that
parameter identification and Recovery
to determine what kinds of experimental
paradigms could resolve that if that was
what we were trying to resolve
um then there's a few more uh
interesting points here
on everything from salience and
neuromodulators and
different pathologies
and they summarize
they outlined an approach to use the
models
previously described to pose questions
to empirical data so chapter 6 was like
the recipe for making the GM and then
here we saw like the kind of second
stage of the recipe
the instructions for model based
analysis
that helped us see like not just the
building of the model which got us to
here
but now we see the whole six stages that
gets us like to the visualization and
statistical analysis that we want in the
paper
um they also highlighted that you can
use these methods to distinguish groups
for example with a given cognitive model
or you can use it to distinguish
alternative model hypotheses given data
from one or more group
they gave a bunch of examples in table
nine one
and they focused on the examples of
atoms and Mirza at all in eye tracking
Pursuit giving just a total clear
example of how even for the very same
data
you can model it with continuous or
discrete time
it's a generic method for experimental
design
that offers an opportunity to answer
questions about the function of the
nervous system and health and disease
okay
that's good for our first discussion on
nine we'll come back next week
and check any
questions that people have added
and uh yeah thanks we'll come back next
week